Jonathan Krause Rare Newspaper and Magazine Collection 1648-1881 E302.1 .J76 E302.1 .J76
Lilly Library
- Colonial American and Early Republic Individuals
  - Thomas Jefferson
    - LETTER TO REPUBLICANS, Independent Chronicle, February 20, 1809 (Item 302)
    - LETTER ON RETIREMENT AS PRESIDENT, National Intelligencer, May 5, 1809 (Item 1000)
    - LETTER TO NEW YORK REPUBLICANS, Independent Chronicle, October 19, 1809 (Item 303)
      See: James Madison 454
    - LETTER ON SCIENCE AND THE PUBLIC, New York Evening Post, March 23, 1812 (Item 1001)
    - LETTER OFFERING HIS LIBRARY TO CONGRESS DURING 1812 WAR AND DEBATE ABOUT LIBRARY PURCHASE, National Intelligencer, October 25, 27, 1814 (Item 304)
    - LETTER OFFERING HIS LIBRARY TO CONGRESS DURING 1812 WAR AND DEBATE ABOUT LIBRARY PURCHASE, Niles' Weekly Register, October 29, 1814; Size: Small (Item 305)
    - LETTER ON FRENCH REVOLUTION AND AMERICAN MANUFACTURES, Independent Chronicle, February 19, 1816 (Item 306)
    - LETTER ON EDUCATION PREVIEWING UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA, Niles' Weekly Register, March 16, 1816; Size: Small (Item 307)
    - LETTER TO GEORGE LOGAN ON THE AFTERMATH OF THE NAPOLEONIC WARS, Niles' Weekly Register, May 18, 1816; Size: Small (Item 1049)
      Jefferson mentions Czar Alexander's capture of Paris, the loss of independence and self-government for certain countries and cities, the continued dominance of the Napoleonic moral code and the British government, and the necessity for America to look after itself.
    - LETTER ON PEACE AND WAR, New York Evening Post, July 10, 1816 (Item 308)
      See John Adams 28
    - LETTER ON PEACE AND WAR, Niles Weekly Register, July 13, 1816; Size: Small (Item 309)
      See John Adams 29
    - LETTER ON AFRICAN COLONIZATION, Niles Weekly Register, April 19, 1817; Size: Small (Item 310)
    - LETTER ON WESTWARD EXPANSION, Independent Chronicle, May 1, 1817 (Item 311)
    - LETTER TO WATERHOUSE ON THE AMERICAN REVOLUTION, SCIENTIFIC DISCOVERY, JOHN ADAMS, AND THE PROCESS OF AGING, New-Hampshire Patriot, December 29, 1818 (Item 1002)
    - LETTER TO MANUEL NOAH ON JEWS AND RELIGIOUS FREEDOM, Niles' Weekly Register, February 20, 1819; Size: Small (Item 312)
      See: John Adams 30 (page 10)
    - PETITION TO CONGRESS AS RECTOR OF UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA, Niles' Weekly Register, December 15, 1821; Size: Small (Item 313)
    - LETTER TO JOHN ADAMS, Columbia Centinel, December 10 (27?), 1823 (Item 315)
      One of few private letters from their correspondence published in a newspaper in their lifetimes.
      2 copies.
    - LETTER TO ADAMS, Niles' Weekly Register, December 21, 1822; Size: Small (Item 314)
    - LETTER ON VIRGINIA CONSTITUTION, Niles Weekly Register, April 23, 1825; Size: Small (Item 316)
      Includes James Madison 467
    - LETTER ON RICHARD OWEN'S UTOPIAN SOCIAL EXPERIMENT, United States Gazette, September 27, 1825 (Item 317)
    - LETTER TO HIS GRANDSON ON HIS ECONOMIC PLIGHT AND PSYCHOLOGICAL CONDITION, National Intelligencer, July 25, 1826 (Item 1003)
  - Anti-Jefferson
    - ANTI-JEFFERSON, The Balance, March 30, April 27, June 15, 1802; Size: Small (Item 318)
    - MAZZEI LETTER, The Balance, April 13, June 1, 1802; Size: Small (Item 319)
    - THREE FIFTHS CLAUSE, The Balance, May 11, August 3, 1802; Size: Small (Item 320)
      Jefferson winning 1800 election because slaves are counted as 3/5 of a human being in the voting, giving a huge advantage to slaveholders.
    - CALLENDER LETTER EXONERATING HIMSELF AND LINK TO JEFFERSON AND EXTRACTS FROM "PROSPECT BEFORE US", The Balance, August 3, 1802; Size: Small (Item 321)
      Attacking Adams and Washington.
    - JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER NO. 1, New York Evening Post, August 3, 1802 (Item 322)
    - JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER NOS. 2 AND 3, New York Evening Post, August 5, 1802 (Item 323)
    - JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER NOS. 4, 5, AND 6, New York Herald, August 11, 1802 (Item 325)
      See: Thomas Jefferson 261
    - JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER NO. 7 AND HISTORY OF CALLENDER FINE AND JEFFERSON'S INVOLVEMENT, The Balance, September 7, 1802; Size: Small (Item 330)
    - CALLENDER LETTER AND JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER NO. 8, The Balance, September 14, 1802; Size: Small (Item 331)
    - JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER NO. 10, Farmer's Museum, October 5, 1802 (Item 338)
      Includes Toussaint Louverture 436 and Napoleon Bonaparte 900
    - JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER NO. 11, Farmer's Museum, October 12, 1802 (Item 341)
      Includes Toussaint Louverture 437 and Napoleon Bonaparte 902
    - CALLENDER LETTER, Farmer's Museum, August 10, 1802 (Item 324)
      He not only broke the story of Sally Hemings but implicated Jefferson shortly before in a corruption scandal where Jefferson had paid and encouraged Callender in his books and articles to attack Adams and Washington with lies and exaggerations
      See: Thomas Jefferson 260
    - CALLENDER LETTER DEFENDING HIMSELF AND ASSERTING JEFFERSON PAID HIS FINE ON RELEASING HIM FROM PRISON AND JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER NO. 5, The Balance, August 24, 1802; Size: Small (Item 328)
    - CALLENDER LETTER, New York Herald, October 2, 1802 (Item 336)
      2 copies (also Aaron Burr 56). Includes Anti-Jefferson 337, and Toussaint Louverture 435, and Napoleon Bonaparte 898
    - CALLENDER LETTER AND BACKGROUND OF CONTROVERSY, The Balance, October 26, 1802; Size: Small (Item 352)
    - CALLENDER AND ANTI-JEFFERSON, New England Palladium, August 13, 1802 (Item 326)
      See: Thomas Jefferson 262
    - JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER, New York Herald, August 21, 1802 (Item 327)
      See: Napoleon Bonaparte 896
    - GENERAL HAMILTON EXONERATED FROM WRITING LETTERS TO WASHINGTON ATTACKING JEFFERSON, New York Herald, October 9, 16, 1802 (Item 339)
      October 9 includes Anti-Jefferson 340 and Anti-Paine 520
      See: Anti-Jefferson 347 for October 16
    - JEFFERSON AND PAINE, New York Herald, October 9, 12, 13, 16, 20, 1802 (Item 340)
      See: Anti-Jefferson 339 (October 9), Anti-Jefferson 344 (October 12), Thomas Jefferson 268 (October 13), and Anti-Jefferson 347 (October 16). Excludes October 20.
    - JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER, The Balance, August 31, 1802; Size: Small (Item 329)
    - CALLENDER ACCUSATIONS AGAINST JEFFERSON, New York Herald, September 25, 1802 (Item 332)
      See: Thomas Jefferson 264
    - ACCUSING JEFFERSON OF NOT BEING SOLE AUTHOR OF DECLARATION OF INDEPENDENCE AND EXONERATING CALLENDER IN HIS CHARGES AGAINST JEFFERSON AND MENTION OF SALLY HEMINGS AND HER FIVE MULATTO CHILDREN AND CARTER'S MOUNTAIN, New York Herald, September 25, 1802 (Item 333)
      Jefferson's cowardice as Governor of Virginia.
    - JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER, The Balance, September 28, 1802; Size: Small (Item 334)
    - JEFFERSON'S COWARDICE IN AMERICAN REVOLUTION AND HYPOCRISY OF HIS WRITINGS, New York Herald, September 29, 1802 (Item 335)
      Includes Napoleon Bonaparte 897
    - DEFENSE OF HAMILTON AGAINST JEFFERSON AND REFERENCES TO SALLY HEMINGS WITHOUT NAMING HER, New York Herald, October 2, 1802 (Item 337)
      See: Aaron Burr 56 or Anti-Jefferson 336 (2 copies)
    - JEFFERSON AND RELIGION, New York Evening Post, October 12, 15, 1802 (Item 342)
      See: Anti-Jefferson 346 (October 15)
    - JEFFERSON AND PAINE, New York Evening Post, October 12, 15, 1802 (Item 343)
      See: Anti-Jefferson 344 (October 12) and Anti-Jefferson 346 (October 15)
    - JEFFERSON ANTI-CONSTITUTION, COWARD, LIAR, New York Evening Post, October 12, 1802 (Item 344)
      About Washington and Hamilton.
      Includes Anti-Jefferson 342 and Anti-Jefferson 343 (October 12)
    - ON CALLENDER AFFAIR AND JEFFERSON'S OPPOSITION TO THE CONSTITUTION, New York Herald, October 13, 20, 1802 (Item 345)
      See: Thomas Jefferson 268 (October 13). Excludes October 20.
    - JEFFERSON INTERFERENCE IN DELAWARE ELECTION, New York Evening Post, October 15, 1802 (Item 346)
      Includes Anti-Jefferson 342, Anti-Jefferson 343, and Anti-Paine 522
    - JEFFERSON'S INTERFERENCE IN DELAWARE ELECTION AND HIS ASSISTANCE TO PAINE, New York Herald, October 16, 1802 (Item 348)
      See: Anti-Jefferson 347
    - MAZZEI LETTER, New York Herald, October 16, 1802 (Item 347)
      Jefferson's attack on Washington.
      Includes Anti-Jefferson 339, Anti-Jefferson 348, Toussaint Louverture 439, and Anti-Paine 523
    - CALLENDER ACCUSATIONS AGAINST JEFFERSON, The Balance, October 19, 1802; Size: Small (Item 349)
    - JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER, Massachusetts Spy, October 20, 1802 (Item 350)
      See: Thomas Jefferson 269
    - SUMMARY OF CHARGES BY CALLENDER AGAINST JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER'S POSITION AS STATED BY THE RICHMOND RECORDER, Farmer's Museum, October 26, 1802 (Item 353)
      See: Thomas Jefferson 270
    - JEFFERSON AND RELIGION, The Balance, November 2, December 14, 21, 1802; Size: Small (Item 354)
    - 1800 ELECTION IMPROPRIETIES, The Balance, November 9, 1802; Size: Small (Item 355)
    - MRS. WALKER AFFAIR, The Balance, November 16, 1802; Size: Small (Item 356)
      As the Republicans had attacked Hamilton in the Reynold's Affair, so the Federalists claimed that during the Revolution, Jefferson unseemly pressed his attentions on the wife of his absent neighbor, who later suggested a duel to remedy the situation, causing Jefferson years later to make his only admission of guilt.
    - MRS. WALKER AFFAIR, The Balance, February 26, April 9, June 11, 18, July 2, 16, 30, 1805; Size: Small (Item 371)
    - SALLY HEMINGS, MRS. WALKER, M. COSWAY IN SAME ISSUE, The Portfolio, January 15, 1803; Size: Small (Item 361)
      Mention of the three women most associated with Jefferson. Maria Cosway, an Italian/English artist and socialite, was the love of Jefferson's life, who met the envoy to France in 1786. Exchanging love letters in the early days, they carried on a random correspondence for the rest of Jefferson's life.
    - JEFFERSON AND PAINE, The Balance, November 30, December 14, 1802; Size: Small (Item 357)
    - LIST OF JEFFERSONIAN ABUSES, The Balance, December 7, 1802; Size: Small (Item 358)
    - ANTI-JEFFERSON, The Portfolio, December 18, 1802, January 1, 15, 1803; Size: Small (Item 359)
    - CALLENDER, The Balance, January 18, 1803; Size: Small (Item 362)
    - ANTI-JEFFERSON, The Balance, February 27, April 12, 1803; Size: Small (Item 363)
    - JEFFERSON'S HYPOCRISY AND JUDICIARY, The Balance, May 10, 1803; Size: Small (Item 364)
    - JEFFERSON AND SLAVERY, The Balance, June 7, 1803; Size: Small (Item 365)
    - QUESTIONABLE MONEY LOAN AND COWARDICE, The Balance, June 21, 1803; Size: Small (Item 366)
    - SEDITION LAW AND DEATH OF CALLENDER, The Balance, August 9, 1803; Size: Small (Item 367)
    - JEFFERSON'S QUESTIONABLE EXPERTISE ON SCIENCE, The Balance, December 13, 27, 1803; Size: Small (Item 368)
      Mountain of Salt.
    - A DEFENSE OF THE LEGISLATURE OF MASSACHUSETTS ON RIGHTS OF NEW ENGLAND, 1804; Size: Small (Item 964)
    - WHO IS ANTI-WASHINGTON? DISMISSAL OF JUDGES, The Balance, January 15, 1805; Size: Small (Item 369)
    - PEACE ACTIONS AND COWARDICE, The Balance, February 5, 1805; Size: Small (Item 370)
    - VIRGINIA AND COWARDICE AND CHARGES BY NEW ENGLAND PALLADIUM, The Balance, February 26, 1805; Size: Small (Item 372)
    - JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER AND NAPOLEON AND LOUISIANA, The Balance, March 5, 1805; Size: Small (Item 373)
    - CALLENDER LETTERS AND NEW YORK EVENING POST VINDICATED FOR LIBELLING JEFFERSON, The Balance, April 9, 1805; Size: Small (Item 374)
    - TRADE EMBARGO AGAINST HAITI, The Balance, April 16, 1805; Size: Small (Item 375)
    - JEFFERSON'S SECOND INAUGURAL AND JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER AND JEFFERSON'S OWN ANTI-JEFFERSON WRITINGS, The Balance, April 30, 1805; Size: Small (Item 376)
    - JEFFERSON LETTER TO REPUBLICAN CRIMINAL, The Balance, May 21, 1805; Size: Small (Item 377)
    - BOSTON REPERTORY DEFENDS CHARGES AGAINST JEFFERSON AND LETTER FROM DISTINGUISHED VIRGINIAN THOMAS TURNER, The Balance, June 18, 1805; Size: Small (Item 378)
    - JEFFERSON'S APPOINTMENTS, The Balance, July 2, 1805; Size: Small (Item 379)
    - COMPARING ADAMS TO JEFFERSON, The Balance, July 16, 1805; Size: Small (Item 380)
    - JEFFERSON AND PAINE, The Balance, July 23, 1805; Size: Small (Item 381)
    - FAILURE TO PROTECT SHIPPING, The Balance, August 6, 1805; Size: Small (Item 382)
    - RELATIONS WITH SPAIN, The Balance, August 20, 1805; Size: Small (Item 383)
    - VINDICATION OF JEFFERSON (ironic) AND SUGGESTION JEFFERSON INTENDED TO SURRENDER VIRGINIA TO ARNOLD DURING REVOLUTIONARY WAR AND CHARGE THAT CALLENDER'S "PROSPECT BEFORE US" ACTUALLY WAS WRITTEN BY JEFFERSON, The Balance, September 17, 1805; Size: Small (Item 384)
    - VINDICATION OF JEFFERSON (ironic), The Balance, September 24, 1805; Size: Small (Item 385)
    - VINDICATION OF JEFFERSON (ironic), The Balance, October 1, 1805; Size: Small (Item 386)
    - VINDICATION OF JEFFERSON (ironic) AND DEFENDING AMERICAN RIGHTS AND INQUIRY INTO HIS CONDUCT, The Balance, October 8, 1805; Size: Small (Item 387)
    - VINDICATION OF JEFFERSON (ironic) AND WHERE IS OUR GOVERNMENT?, The Balance, October 22, 1805; Size: Small (Item 388)
    - THOMAS TURNER'S RESPONSE TO VINDICATION OF JEFFERSON, The Balance, November 5, 1805; Size: Small (Item 389)
    - EVILS OF JEFFERSON'S FRIEND JOEL BARLOW, The Balance, November 19, 1805; Size: Small (Item 390)
    - AMERICA AND SPAIN AND ANTI-BARLOW, The Balance, November 26, 1805; Size: Small (Item 391)
    - OUR INCOMPETENT ADMINISTRATION, The Balance, December 3, 1805; Size: Small (Item 392)
    - JEFFERSON'S SUPPORT OF DUANE AS JASPER DWIGHT IN ATTACKING WASHINGTON AND ASSISTING PAINE IN HIS ATTACKS AND CALLENDER AND OUR POSITION IN THE WORLD, The Balance, December 10, 1805; Size: Small (Item 393)
    - JEFFERSON'S WEAKNESS AT HOME AND TIMIDITY IN FOREIGN RELATIONS, The Balance, December 24, 1805; Size: Small (Item 394)
    - MR. GARDINIER'S SPEECH, 1808; Size: Small (Item 971)
    - CORRESPONDENCE BETWEEN GOVERNOR SULLIVAN AND TIMOTHY PICKERING, 1808; Size: Small (Item 972)
      In which the latter vindicates himself against the groundless charges and insinuations made by the governor and other.
    - LETTER FROM TIMOTHY PICKERING TO HIS CONSTITUENTS ON EMBARGO, 1808; Size: Small (Item 974)
    - MR. HILLHOUSE'S SPEECH ON THE RESOLUTION TO REPEAL THE EMBARGO, November 29, 1808; Size: Small (Item 976)
    - MR. PICKERING'S SPEECH IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES, ON THE RESOLUTION OFFERED BY MR. HILLHOUSE TO REPEAL THE SEVERAL ACTS LAYING AN EMBARGO, November 30, 1808; Size: Small (Item 973)
    - CONGRESSMAN LIVERMORE'S SPEECH ON EMBARGO, 1809; Size: Small (Item 978)
    - MR. QUINCY'S SPEECH IN THE HOUSE, 1809; Size: Small (Item 979)
  - James Madison
    - INAUGURAL ADDRESS, United States Gazette for the Country, March 9, 1809 (Item 453)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, Massachusetts Spy, December 6, 1809 (Item 455)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, Connecticut Mirror, December 10, 1810 (Item 456)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, Connecticut Mirror, November 11, 1811 (Item 457)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, Weekly Messenger, November 13, 1812 (Item 458)
    - SECOND INAUGURAL ADDRESS, The War (New York), March 16, 1813 (Item 459)
      Plus famous correspondence between Captain Bainbridge of USS Constitution and British General Hislop of the Java.
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, Columbian Centinel, December 11, 1813 (Item 460)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, The Yankee, September 30, 1814 (Item 462)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, Columbian Centinel, December 9, 1815 (Item 464)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, Columbian Centinel, December 11, 1816 (Item 465)
    - HELVIDIUS I (the Helvidius-Pacificus [Hamilton] essays), Gazette of the United States, August 24, 28, 1793 (Item 447)
      The above essays represent the most famous and significant constitutional debate in American history.
    - HELVIDIUS II, Gazette of the United States, August 31, 1793 (Item 448)
      2 copies. Includes Alexander Hamilton 191
    - HELVIDIUS III, Gazette of the United States, September 7, 1793 (Item 449)
    - HELVIDIUS IV, Gazette of the United States, September 14, 1793 (Item 450)
      Includes Alexander Hamilton 192
    - HELVIDIUS V, Gazette of the United States, September 18, 1793 (Item 451)
    - ANNOUNCES PROPOSING AMENDMENT TO CONSTITUTION, American Museum Magazine, May 1789; Size: Small (Item 444)
      See: Benjamin Franklin 121
    - ON THE BANK BILL, Gazette of the United States, April 20, 1791 (Item 445)
      Includes John Adams 9
    - SPEECH TO THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES ON HAMILTON, Gazette of the United States, March 27, 1793 (Item 446)
      Includes French Revolution 945
    - TWO LETTERS AS SECRETARY OF STATE REGARDING EMBARGO, New York Herald, November 19, 1808 (Item 452)
    - PROVINCIAL PARLIAMENT OF LOWER CANADA SPEECH, LIEUTENANT ALEXANDER CONTEE HANSON'S DEFENCE, DECLARATION OF WAR BY FRANCIS OF AUSTRIA (WAR OF THE FIFTH COALITION), New York Herald, June 10, 1809 (Item 980)
    - SAMUEL SMITH AND JAMES BUCHANAN CORRESPONDENCE CONDEMNING JAMES WILKINSON, REPORT ON DANGERS OF SLAVE TRADE FROM CUBA BY NEW ORLEANS CORRESPONDENT, New York Herald, August 19, 1809 (Item 981)
    - CONGRESS EXTENDING EMBARGO ON GREAT BRITAIN AND FRANCE, EXTRACTS FROM HALIFAX PAPERS, New York Herald, August 23, 1809 (Item 982)
    - LETTER TO NEW YORK REPUBLICANS, Independent Chronicle, October 19, 1809 (Item 454)
      Includes Thomas Jefferson 303
    - DECLARATION OF THE COUNTY OF ESSEX, MASSCHUSETTS BY THE DELEGATES ASSEMBLED IN CONVENTION, 1812; Size: Small (Item 983)
    - AN ADDRESS OF MEMBERS OF THE HOUSE TO THEIR CONSTITUENTS ON THE SUBJECT OF THE WAR WITH GREAT BRITAIN, 1812; Size: Small (Item 984)
    - PROCLAMATION RECOMMENDING A DAY OF PRAYER, Niles Weekly Register, July 31, 1813; Size: Small (Item 1036)
      One of Madison's most religious utterances, similar in its religiosity to those found in Washington, Adams, and Lincoln.
    - PROCLAMATION ON BURNING OF WASHINGTON, D.C., Weekly Aurora, September 13, 1814 (Item 461)
      Includes War of 1812 745
    - THE PROCEEDINGS OF A CONVENTION OF DELEGATES (THE HARTFORD CONVENTION) DISCUSSING A NEW ENGLAND SECESSION AND A CLOSE ASSOCIATION WITH ENGLAND, FROM THE STATES OF MASSACHUSETTS, CONNECTICUT, AND RHODE-ISLAND; THE COUNTIES OF CHESHIRE AND GRAFTON, IN THE STATE OF NEW-HAMPSHIRE; AND THE COUNTY OF WINDHAM, IN THE STATE OF VERMONT; CONVENED AT HARTFORD, IN THE STATE OF CONNECTICUT, December 15, 1814, 1815; Size: Small (Item 985)
    - MESSAGE TO CONGRESS ON TREATY OF GHENT, Boston Patriot, March 4, 1815 (Item 463)
      Ending War of 1812.
    - LETTER TO MANUEL NOAH ON JEWS AND RELIGIOUS FREEDOM, Niles' Weekly Register, February 20, 1819; Size: Small (Item 466)
    - LETTER ON VIRGINIA CONSTITUTION, Niles Weekly Register, April 23, 1825; Size: Small (Item 467)
      See: Thomas Jefferson 316
    - LETTER ON THE CONSTITUTION, Massachusetts Yeoman, January 3, 1829 (Item 468)
      Late analysis of the Constitution during the nullification controversy.
    - LETTER ON THE CONSTITUTION, Banner of the Constitution, October 20, 1830 (Item 469)
      Historic final word on the Constitution by the father of the Constitution.
    - LETTER TO INGERSOLL ON STATE POWER TO MAKE BANKS AND FEDERAL CONSTITUTIONAL ISSUES, Western Statesman, April 15, 1831 (Item 470)
  - James Monroe
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE (MONROE DOCTRINE), Columbian Centinel, December 10, 1823 (Item 475)
      See: Thomas Jefferson 315
    - VINDICATION OF JEFFERSON, Gazette of the United States, September 26, 1792 (Item 471)
      Includes French Revolution 941
    - VINDICATION OF JEFFERSON, Gazette of the United States, December 8, 1792 (Item 472)
    - VINDICATION OF JEFFERSON, Gazette of the United States, January 5, 1793 (Item 473)
    - CORRESPONDENCE WITH JEFFERSON, American Citizen, November 2, 1808 (Item 474)
      See: Thomas Jefferson 299
  - Thomas Paine
    - APPENDIX TO THE PAMPHLET TITLED COMMON SENSE WITH AN ADDRESS TO THE QUAKERS, Norwich Packet, April 8, 1776 - April 15, 1776 (Item 476)
      Bradford Edition of February 14, 1776, containing an additional 30 percent of material (the appendix and letter to the Quakers). Paine's celebrated biographer, David Freeman Hawke, said: "In the last line of the Appendix every American was asked to become...a virtuous supporter of the rights of mankind, and of the free and independent states of America."
    - EXCERPTS FROM COMMON SENSE, Edinburgh Evening Courant, April 15, 1776; Size: Small (Item 477)
      First UK printing.
    - PLAIN TRUTH GIVES TORY RESPONSE TO COMMON SENSE, London Chronicle, June 6, 1776; Size: Small (Item 478)
    - AMERICAN CRISIS III, Providence Gazette, May 31, 1777 (Item 479)
    - AMERICAN CRISIS VII, Connecticut Gazette, December 4, 1778 (Item 481)
    - SATIRIC POLITICAL POEM TO GOVERNOR JOHNSTONE, Providence Gazette, August 22, 1778; Size: Small (Item 480)
      Includes Revolutionary War 628
    - LETTER ON SILAS DEANE, Connecticut Journal, January 13, 1779 (Item 482)
      Broadsheet.
    - LETTER VINDICATING COMMON SENSE, AMERICAN CRISIS AND SUPPORT OF INDEPENDENCE AND SILAS DEANE AFFAIR, Pennsylvania Packet, September 14, 1779 (Item 483)
    - LETTER AS CLERK OF THE PENNSYLVANIA GENERAL ASSEMBLY REGARDING POSSIBLE EMERGENCY POWERS OF THE PRESIDENT AND VICE-PRESIDENT OF PENNSYLVANIA DURING THE REVOLUTIONARY WAR, London Magazine, August 1780 (Item 1046)
      Size: Small
    - COMMON SENSE ON FINANCING THE WAR, Freeman's Journal or the North-American Intelligencer, March 13, 1782 (Item 484)
    - LETTER TO SIR GUY CARLETON, Independent Gazeteer, June 8, 1782 (Item 485)
      Includes George Washington 549
    - LETTER TO CINCINATUS ON BRITISH AND AMERICAN COMMERCE, The Continental Journal & Weekly Advertiser, May 6, 1784 (Item 1034)
      Comments from Mr. Krause: I believe this might be a letter by Paine. In the first line of the letter Common Sense (Paine ?) intends to write a reply to Lord Sheffield's pamphlet, but four months before in December, 1783, he has already written a reply. The style is close enough to be Paine, but others have used the Common Sense pseudonym. Many of Paine's lesser works are almost impossible to find (and not listed in his Complete Works). The Gimble collection of Thomas Paine Papers at the American Philosophical Society may be able to shed more light.
      See: George Washington 993
    - LETTER ON THE BANK OF THE U.S., Pennsylvania Packet, December 17, 1785 (Item 486)
    - EXCERPTS FROM RIGHTS OF MAN, PART I, Columbian Magazine, April 1791; Size: Small (Item 487)
      See: Alexander Hamilton 157
    - DEDICATION TO WASHINGTON OF THE RIGHTS OF MAN, Columbian Centinel, May 4, 1791 (Item 488)
    - LETTER TO ABBE SIEYES, New York Journal, September 14, 1791 (Item 489)
      Includes Joseph Priestly 535
    - LETTER TO ABBE SIEYES, Columbian Centinel, September 17, 1791 (Item 490)
      See: Joseph Priestly 536
    - LETTER TO ABBE SIEYES, Massachusetts Spy, September 29, 1791 (Item 491)
      Includes Joseph Priestly 537
    - LETTER TO THE AUTHORS OF "LE REPUBLICAIN," Columbian Centinel, October 12, 1791 (Item 1027)